# **Clayton Long**

# Inside Sales Engineer at CATERPILLER-ISO

Burlington, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Clayton-Long/9be35c984201a87a

Highly proficient account manager noted for positioning products to both the business and technical end users. Experienced sales engineer with proven technical and sales growth experience. Focused problem solver, combining analytical, organizational, technical and interpersonal skills to achieve key business objectives. Areas of expertise include:

- Relationship Building Customer Service \* Creative / Strategic Solution Selling
- \* Territory Development \* Sales Presentations \* Strategic Alliance Development
- \* Productivity Improvement \* Client Needs Analysis \* New Product Introduction
- \* Product Management \*Outside Sales \*Inside Sales \* Excellent Communication Skills

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Sales Engineer

CATERPILLER-ISO - Alpharetta, GA - January 2008 to April 2011

Interpret engineering specifications for CAT, Eaton, Zenith, ASCO, Russelectric, Generac, Cutler-Hammer and competitor product line technologies, then positioned products to both the business and technical end users. Identified technical and communication gaps in specifications and corrected them to ensure customer satisfaction throughout final sales and operations. Researched and developed profile of competitor's win strategy and made recommendations for pricing, quality, and aftermarket business, using comparative or superior product proposals, according to specific technical needs and data. Managed accounts and relationships with CAT dealers, teaming partners, subcontractors, and third parties, to ensure product offer positioning against competitor product line pricing to win bids, and contracts. Coordinated with product managers via process after final sales. Quoted and negotiated pricing for dealers and site engineers for ATS, Medium and low-voltage switchboards for paralleling Switch Gear projects.

- Surpassed goals for 2008-2010, achieving 22% marginal profit goals on 15% expected.
- Total profit growth for 2010 was 143% on SE Caterpillar Dealer accounts assigned.
- Supported pricing and subjective communications for AIS, GIS and Pass MO's.
- Supported Modbus and TCP/IP, and Ethernet for communications, compatible with Eaton-CAT products and competitor product line. Proficient in UL-1008.

## Sr. Account Manager

W.W. GRAINGER - Robbinsville, NJ - 2004 to 2008

Managed 366 accounts for W.W. Grainger generating \$2.9M in revenue for commercial, manufacturing and contractor segments. Managed SE division of Grainger (Alpharetta) Jan 2008 to head customer base in contracting market segment. Managed 256 customer-base accounts, and numerous vendors. Superuser in SAP and other CRM's, and ARIBA purchasing systems. Supplied tech knowledge and training and development of new hires and supported company directives for growth in contractor base market.

- Surpassed account goals expectation of 100% with total growth ending 117.4%.
- Successfully headed NYC market with highest V% 2004-2007.
- Achieved 110.3% growth success rate in new business acquisitions.

### Sales accommodation awards

W.W. GRAINGER - 2004 to 2007

2004-2008

W.W. GRAINGER - 2004 to 2007

-2007

## Sr. Tech Sales Associate

ROHM & HAAS Co - 1999 to 2004

Represented Company in gaining major customer accounts by technical experimentation and formulation of products and product pricing. Organized outside contract services. Procured operational assets and accounting for sales tech service and research department accounts. Managed the ERP system for Sales Tech Team. Serviced field sales representatives in NAR sector. Targeted potential clients for sales. Formulated products to meet customer satisfaction, performed demonstrations. Worked closely with Marketing Teams and ERP Teams, and EHS Safety Councils.

- Played key role in increasing company earnings by 18%.
- Co-authored, "Synthesis and Characterization of Mixed metal Oxide Catalysts for Propane Selective Oxidation" patent.
- Recipient of numerous Rohm Haas Company and Departmental awards.

ROHM & HAAS Co - 1988 to 1999

Operated Gas Chromatography equipment. Conducted the Nuclear Magnetic Resonance to split and identify carbon molecules. Identified chemical impurities using the Infrared Molecular counter. Simulated for research and customer base experimentation, ensuring the marketing ability of said products. Highly skilled in HPLC, GC, IR and NMR operation. Proficient -other testing equipment.

Monomers Research Tech R&D - 1987 to 1987

1987)

Performed recovery of acryl ate /alcohol values from High Temperature Separation/Esters streams. Worked with the patent department on the preparation and publication of a "Research Disclosure" for anti-sedimentation agents.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Business Organization**

University of Phoenix

## **Liberal Arts/Sciences**

Rider University

#### **SKILLS**

Computers, Lotus Notes, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, HTML, Access, SAP, Oracle, Ariba, Mini-Tab and ERP systems. Semi-Proficient Spanish.

#### **LINKS**

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/clayton-long-jr/25/822/701